# Archana.G.S Data Scientist

Portfolio Linkedin Upwork Github Published paper

Milpitas,CA 669 231 9980 archanags001@gmail.com

Data Scientist with over 4 years of experience, specializing in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Demonstrated success in creating machine learning models, conducting in-depth data analysis, and applying problem-solving skills. Eager to contribute my expertise to the dynamic and challenging field of AI.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Data Scientist** — **Wonder Chrome** (December 2021 - PRESENT)

- Conducted A/B testing experiments to assess the effectiveness of various promotion strategies, resulting in a remarkable 24% increase in revenue.
- Developed machine learning models using scikit-learn to optimize pricing strategies, leading to a substantial 12% boost in profit.
- Led full data lifecycle: collection, cleaning, feature engineering, modeling, validation, and dashboard/report creation.
- Proficiently developed complex SQL queries, procedures, and reports using Redshift, Sagemaker, SQL, and Python to meet diverse client needs.
- Developed a Large-scale multi-label text classification model using Tensorflow and Keras to enhance text analysis capabilities.

## Data Scientist — Freelance (January 2019 - PRESENT) Upwork

- Top Rated freelancer, representing the top 10% of Upwork talent.
- Collaborated with 5 clients to understand their company needs and devise data-driven solutions.
- Facilitated end-to-end development, testing, and monitoring of analytical models for 5 clients.
- Designed and developed a News search tool leveraging LLM and Langchain technologies, enhancing the efficiency of information retrieval and analysis.
- Efficiently managed Azure Databricks, executed ETL, and developed ML models for small and large datasets(125GB, 1B rows), automated scheduling, tracked experiments, implemented Auto ML, and maintained resource efficiency

## Artificial Intelligence Engineer intern — Uniquify Inc(August 2021-October 2021)

- Led training and development of neural networks using TensorFlow, optimizing models for enhanced accuracy and efficiency.
- Conducted comprehensive experiments with TensorFlow scripts and analyzed results to enhance model performance and understand framework dynamics.
- Played a key role in debugging and improving an automation framework for neural network and TensorFlow scripts, streamlining workflows and ensuring reliable model training.
- Developed advanced image processing and segmentation algorithms to solve complex problems, contributing to project success.

# **Data Analyst** — Centriqe Inc (February 2020 - January 2021)

- Developed an NLP system using NLTK to automate text analysis, resulting in a significant 39% reduction in manual analysis efforts, improving efficiency and accuracy.
- Leveraged analytical and technical expertise to provide actionable insights and proposals, driving business improvement strategies.
- Designed and implemented a range of predictive models, including classification and forecasting models, using various machine learning tools to solve complex business challenges.
- Identified trends, key metrics, and critical data points, generating insightful
  dashboards using a variety of data visualization tools to facilitate data-driven
  decision-making.

#### **SKILLS**

## **Programming Languages:**

Python, R, Core Java, Basic JavaScript

Machine Learning and DeepLearning: TensorFlow, Keras, CNN, RNN, PyTorch

# **Natural Language Processing**

(NLP): NLP techniques, Hugging Face, Langchain, Transfer learning,SpaCy, BeautifulSoup

Computer Vision: OpenCV, Transfer learning,YOLO, VGG16, ResNet

Generative AI: LLM, Langchain, Hugging Face, OpenAI, Gemini, LLAMA

Cloud Services: AWS, Azure

**Database & Data Storage:** SQL, MongoDB

Data Visualization Tools:

Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn

Big Data: PySpark

## **Dashboard Development:**

Power BI, Tableau, Retool, Dash, Streamlit, Kibana

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Technology in Electronics with specialization in Signal processing

**GPA: 4.0** 

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication

Engineering **GPA**: 3.5

## **WORK ELIGIBILITY:**

**EAD**(Employment Authorization Document)